Meany, George. Center for Labor Studies Interviews. 6036/026
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Meany, George. Center for Labor Studies Interviews.
1979-1986
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
George Meany Center for Labor Studies Oral History Project
6036/026
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence, photographs.
This collection contains full and partial transcripts of oral history interviews conducted by the George Meany Center for Labor Studies. Included are interviews with ILGWU staff and officers.
5770071
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 29, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 10, 2013
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Scope and Contents
The collection contains interviews conducted in 1979 and 1980 for the George Meany Center for Labor Studies Oral History Project. The oral history projects main focus is on the AFL and CIO merger. Not all of the transcripts reproduced for this collection include the complete interview, but only select pages in which the interviewees mention or discuss the garment industry, the ILGWU and its members or officers, and particularly David Dubinsky. Individuals interviewed are: Jack Barbash, Andrew Biemiller, Harry Block, Jack Conway, Nelson Cruikshank, Joseph Curran, Evelyn Dubrow, Katherine Pollak Ellickson, Harry Fleisher, Douglas Fraser, Arthur Goldberg, Patrick E. Gorman, Hilton Hanna, A.J. Hayes, Henry Kaiser, Joseph Keenan, John W. Livingston, David J. McDonald, Lee Webb Minton, Robert Oliver, James C. Petrillo, Leon Stein, Abe Raskin, George Weaver, and Charles Zimmerman.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records
Barbash, Jack; Biemiller, Andrew J. -- (Andrew John), -- 1906-1982.; Aronoson, Irwin.; Conway, Jack T.; Cruikshank, Nelson.; Curran, Joseph.; Dubrow, Evelyn.; Ellickson, Katherine Pollak, -- 1905-; Hoffman, Alice M., -- 1929-; Walsh, Joan.; Fleisher, Henry.; Kennedy, Don.; Fraser, Douglas.; Conn, Dick.; Goldberg, Arthur.; Gorman, Patrick Emmet, -- 1892-1980.; Adelman, William.; Hayes, Albert J. -- (Albert John), -- 1900-1981.; Kaiser, Henry J., -- 1892-; McDonald, David J. -- (David John), -- 1902-1979.; Lucheck, Anthony.; Minton, Lee Webb.; Remington, John.; Stein, Leon, -- 1912-; Raskin, Abe.; Weaver, George L. P.; Addis, Paul.; Zimmerman, Charles S., -- 1896-1983.; George Meany Center for Labor Studies
5770071
- Jack Barbash, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  #26 R.I. 1. Interviewed by James Cavanaugh on February 2 and 9, 1979. Excerpts.
- Andrew Biemiller, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  #26 R.I. 2. Interviewed by Alice Hoffman on May 22, 1979. Excerpts.
- Harry Block, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  #26 R.I. 3. Interviewed by Irwin Aronson on April 11, 1979. Excerpts.
- Jack Conway, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  #26 R.I. 4. Interviewed by Alice Hoffman on May 23, 1979. Excerpts.
- Nelson Cruikshank, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  #26 R.I. 5. Interviewed by James Cavanaugh on August 21, 1979. Excerpts.
- Joseph Curran, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  #26 R.I. 6. Interviewed by Richard Conn on February 2, 1980. Excerpts.
- Evelyn Dubrow, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  #26 R.I. 7. Interviewed by Alice Hoffman on March 20, 1979. 22 pages.
- Katherine Pollak Ellickson, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  #26 R.I. 8. Interviewed by Joan Walsh Goldman on May 4, 1979. Excerpts.
- Henry Fleisher, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  #26 R.I. 9. Interviewed by Don Kennedy on May 4, 1979. Excerpts.
- Douglas Fraser, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  #26 R.I. 10. Interviewed by Dick Conn on January 14, 1980. Excerpts.
- Arthur Goldberg, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  #26 R.I. 11. Interviewed by Alice Hoffman on October 9, 1979. 21 pages.
- Patrick Gorman and Hilton Hanna, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  #26 R.I. 12. Interviewed by William Adelman on May 25, 1979. Excerpts.
- A.J. Hayes, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  #26 R.I. 13. Interviewed by James Cavanaugh on May 4, 1979. Excerpts.
- A.J. Hayes, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  #26 R.I. 14. Interviewed by Gordon Cole on December 13, 1979. Excerpts.
- Henry Kaiser, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  #26 R.I. 15. Interviewed by William Adelman on August 10, 1979. Excerpts.
- Joseph Keenan, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  #26 R.I. 16. Interviewed by Miles Galvin on July 23, 1979. Excerpts.
- John W. Livingston, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  #26 R.I. 17. Interviewed by Paul Addis on September 28, 1978. Excerpts.
- David J. McDonald, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  #26 R.I. 18. Interviewed by Anthony Luchek on February 7, 1979. Excerpts.
- Lee Webb Minton, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  #26 R.I. 19. Interviewed by John Remington on September 6, 1979. Excerpts.
- Robert Oliver, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  #26 R.I. 20. Interviewed by Frank Fernbach on September 17, 1979. Excerpts.
- James Petrillo, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  #26 R.I. 21. Interviewed by William Adelman on August 23, 1979. Excerpts.
- Leon Stein, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  #26 R.I. 22. Interviewed by Jon Bloom on March 8, 1979. 18 pages.
- Abe Raskin, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  #26 R.I. 23. Interviewed by Jon Bloom on April 18, 1979. 28 pages.
- George L.P. Weaver, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  #26 R.I. 24. Interviewed by Paul Addis on May 18, 1979. Excerpts.
- Charles Zimmerman, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  #26 R.I. 25. Interviewed by Miles Galvin on May 8, 1979. 21 pages.
- Charles Zimmerman, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  #26 R.I. 26. Interviewed by Miles Galvin on May 8, 1979. 7 pages.
- Letters from Katherine Vogel of the George Meany Memorial Archives, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)